openbadges.org 2016-04-12

# None

This section is a summary of our privacy practices about the Mozilla Badge Backpack that are described more fully below. However, please be sure to read the entire document, because when you use the Mozilla Badge Backpack, you are indicating you are ok with our whole privacy policy, not just this summary: 

  * You need to sign in with your Persona account to use the Mozilla Badge Backpack. For more info about Persona’s privacy practices, please [see here](http://www.mozilla.org/en-US/persona/privacy-policy/).
  * The Mozilla Badge Backpack is only available to users over 13.
  * Each badge you push to the Mozilla Badge Backpack contains your Persona username and data about what the badge means and who issued it.

## Mozilla Badge Backpack Privacy Policy

### April 4, 2012

This policy describes how Mozilla handles the information we collect about you when you use the Mozilla Badge Backpack. We have separate privacy policies for our other products and services, please [see here](http://www.mozilla.org/privacy/websites/) for more. 

Some words we use in this policy that you should know: 

  * The Open Badge Infrastructure or OBI is the underlying technology that supports badge issuing, collection, and display. The OBI is defined by two aspects: (i) the Open Badge specification, which technically describes an Open Badge standard and (ii) a Badge Backpack, which is a service that provides badge earners a way to collect and manage badges. To learn more about OBI, [click here](http://openbadges.org/legal_faq.html).
  * A badge is a digital symbol of recognition.
  * An Earner is anyone that earns a badge and uses the Mozilla Badge Backpack.
  * An Issuer is a person or entity that issues or awards badges which you can then send to your Mozilla Badge Backpack. Most badges are issued by third parties but, in some cases, Mozilla issues badges.
  * A Badge Backpack is a repository for collecting and displaying badges from a variety of sources and is a user management interface where you can collect, delete, group badges and more. 
  * The Mozilla Badge Backpack is a Badge Backpack hosted by Mozilla. The first time you agree to push a badge into the Mozilla Badge Backpack from an issuer, your Mozilla Badge Backpack is created and when this happens, that issuer will transmit certain information about you to us as described in this privacy policy. If you believe badges have been sent to your backpack without your consent, let us know by sending us an email at [openbadges@mozilla.org](mailto:openbadges@mozilla.org).

## Personal Information

Personal information is either:

  1. information which identifies you, like your name or email address; or
  2. a combination of several pieces of information which couldn't identify you on their own, but which might identify you when combined together.

If we store personal information with other information that is not personal, we treat the combination like personal information. 

## What information is stored in a badge?

Each badge in the Mozilla Badge Backpack will contain a Persona username, the Issuer’s name, the badge name and other data about what the badge means. Every badge you send to us is “private” by default in your backpack, and cannot be accessed publicly until you choose to share it. You can click on a badge to view the kinds of information contained in it. 

  * For a more detailed explanation of what badges contain and how issuers send them to us, [see here](https://github.com/mozilla/openbadges/wiki/Issuer-API).
  * To learn more about sharing badges, see here.
  * To learn more about Persona, [click here](http://www.mozilla.org/en-US/persona/). Persona has it’s own privacy policy and you can read it [here](http://www.mozilla.org/en-US/persona/privacy-policy/).

## Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor's computer, and that the visitor's browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Most major websites use cookies. Because the browser provides this cookie information to the website at each visit, cookies serve as a sort of label that allows a website to "recognize" a browser when it returns to the site. The domain name in Mozilla cookies will clearly identify their affiliation with Mozilla and, where applicable, its third-party service provider. 

Mozilla uses cookies to help us identify visitors and pair features with their website access preferences across multiple requests and visits to the Mozilla Badge Backpack. 

Mozilla uses the information provided by cookies to develop a better understanding of how Mozilla's visitors use Mozilla's websites, and to facilitate those visitors' interactions with Mozilla's websites. 

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Mozilla visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers by Mozilla, its contractors, or third-party service providers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before linking to the Mozilla Badge Backpack. The Mozilla Badge Backpack may not function properly without the aid of cookies. 

## How we collect information about you when you use the Mozilla Badge Backpack

There are four general ways we get information about you: 

  * You give it to us directly, like when you give us your email address when you log in;
  * We collect it automatically, like when we collect information about queries to our website such as an IP address;
  * Someone else tells us something about you, like when badge issuers tell us information about the badge you earned; or
  * We try and understand more about you based on information you've already given us, like guessing that you're in the US because you have a US IP address.

## What we will do with your info

We use your information to help us provide the Mozilla Badge Backpack to you. When you give us personal information, we will only use it for the reasons we told you about when you gave it to us, including as described in this policy. 

## When we share your info

Mozilla is an open organization. We publicly release de-identified user information to make our products better and help foster an open web, but only in a way that we think respects the privacy of our users. Whenever we release information about our users in this way, we'll remove information that we believe can identify you and try to minimize the risk of you being re-identified. 

We may share your personal information with employees, contractors, partners and service providers but only if they are contractually obligated to handle the data in ways that are approved by Mozilla. If our organizational structure or status changes (like if we undergo a restructuring, are acquired, or go bankrupt) we'll pass on your information to a successor or affiliate. 

We also share your information when you ask us to, like when you make a badge public. When you choose to share badges, please remember, that while we encrypt your Persona username in that public badge, that encrypted username and other information in the badges will be available to third parties. 

We may also access, use, preserve or disclose information about you when we have a good faith belief that it is reasonably necessary to do so to satisfy the applicable law, regulation, legal process or lawful governmental request of any country, or to protect the rights, property or safety of Mozilla, its users or the public. 

## How we store and protect your info

We take steps to make sure that anyone (like an employee or contractor) we show your personal information has a good reason to see it and is only allowed to do Mozilla-approved things with it. 

Despite our efforts, we can't guarantee that hackers can't break in and access your data. If we find out about a security breach, we'll try hard to let you know so that you can take appropriate protective steps. We only keep information as long as we need to do the thing we collected it for. Once we don't need it any more, we'll destroy it unless we are forced by law to keep it longer. 

## Your Choices; Deleting your Badges and/or Account

We try to give you as much choice and control around your data as we can. Many of the choices you can make with respect to your privacy for the Mozilla Badge Backpack are stated throughout this policy. 

You can delete any badge from your backpack you wish to. This action is irreversible unless you are able to persuade the issuer to re-issue the deleted badge(s) to you. Also, if you would like to stop using the Mozilla Badge Backpack, you can choose to delete all of your badges at any time. Be careful with this functionality–once you delete your backpack, it will be gone for good! If you delete your Persona account, please note that that will not delete your Mozilla Badge Backpack, but will cause you not to be able to log in to access your Mozilla Badge Backpack unless you create a new Persona account with the exact same username. 

Please note that if you want to delete a badge or your account from another backpack provider or issuer, you must contact such issuer or backpack to delete that badge from that account or issuer. 

## International Privacy

Privacy laws and expectations vary from country to country. We're a global company and our computers are in several different places around the world. We also use service providers whose computers may also be in various countries. This means that any information we have about you might end up on one of those computers in another country, and that country may have a different level of data protection regulation than yours. 

## Legal Process

When a government agency or someone involved in a lawsuit asks for your personal info, we'll only give it to them if we have a good faith belief that: 

  * the law requires us to, or
  * it is reasonably necessary to do so to prevent harm to someone.

We follow the law whenever we receive requests like this about you and we'll notify you any time we are asked to hand over your personal info like this, unless we're legally prohibited from doing so or circumstances require otherwise. 

We may also access, use, preserve or disclose information about you when we have a good faith belief that it is reasonably necessary to do so to protect the rights, property or safety of Mozilla, its users or the public. 

## Children

The services made available through the Mozilla Badge Backpack are not directed to individuals under the age of 13 and you should not use the Mozilla Badge Backpack if you are under 13. If you are a parent or legal guardian and believe that your child who is under 13 has provided us with personally identifiable information, please contact us at [openbadges@mozilla.org](mailto:openbadges@mozilla.org). 

## Changes to this policy

Sometimes, we change our privacy policies. When we do, we may notify you on the Mozilla Badge Backpack or, in some cases, through email. You should come back to check for changes. 

## Contact us

If you want to make a correction to your information, or you have any questions about our privacy policies, please get in touch with: 

Mozilla Corporation

Attn: Legal Notices—Privacy

331 E. Evelyn Ave.

Mountain View, CA 94041

Phone: +1-650-903-0800
